<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SDN on Huabing Blog</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/tags/sdn/</link><description>Recent content in SDN on Huabing Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/tags/sdn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Network Service Mesh: A Big Step Toward Cloud-Native NFV</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2020-02-21-network-service-mesh-english/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2020-02-21-network-service-mesh-english/</guid><description>&lt;p>When hearing about the term “Network Service Mesh” for the first time, you probably are as curious as I was: What exactly is it behind this fancy name? Does it have anything to do with Service Mesh/Istio? It turns out that Network Service Mesh is a sandbox project in the CNCF (Cloud Native Foundation), and it’s also a new hotspot in the cloud-native area. In this post, I’ll dive into the architecture and technical details of Network Service Mesh, and also explore the relationship between it and some other similar technologies you might get confused with, including Service Mesh, SDN, and NFV.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NFV迈向云原生时代：Network Service Mesh项目介绍</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2020-02-15-network-service-mesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2020-02-15-network-service-mesh/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="前言">前言&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>当第一次看到Network Service Mesh这一名词时，你很可能和我一样好奇它到底是什么？是否和Service Mesh有什么关系？Network Service Mesh是云原生领域中一个新的热点，是CNCF（云原生基金会）中的一个沙箱项目。本文将介绍Network Service Mesh的起源和架构，并探讨其与Service Mesh、SDN、NFV等相关技术的区别与联系。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Can Service Mesh Learn from SDN?</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2019-11-23-what-can-service-mesh-learn-from-sdn-english/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2019-11-23-what-can-service-mesh-learn-from-sdn-english/</guid><description>&lt;p>Service Mesh is yet another emerging fancy tech word in the field of microservices recently. If you have a telecommunication or networking background, you may have already noticed that Service Mesh and SDN (Software Defined Network) look similar. Both of them use a software layer to manage and control the network infrastructure, and they also share the same architecture, which consists of a control plane and a data plane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what is the relationship between Service Mesh and SDN — Is Service Mesh the next generation of SDN? What can Service Mesh learn from the experience of SDN? I’d like to share some of my own opinions in this article.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Service Mesher Meetup 成都站：Service Mesh是下一代SDN吗？</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2019-10-26-what-can-service-mesh-learn-from-sdn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2019-10-26-what-can-service-mesh-learn-from-sdn/</guid><description>&lt;p>如果具有通信或者网络行业的知识背景，那么你对SDN(Software Defined Network)一定不会陌生。你也许已经注意到，近来在微服务领域兴起的Service Mesh和SDN(Software Defined Network) 非常相似，这两者都采用了软件对网络进行管理和控制，也都采用了包含控制面和数据面的类似架构。&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>