<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ONAP on Huabing Blog</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/tags/onap/</link><description>Recent content in ONAP on Huabing Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/tags/onap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Secure ONAP Microservices with Istio Mutual TLS Authentication and RBAC</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2018-08-15-manage-onap-with-istio-auth-enabled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2018-08-15-manage-onap-with-istio-auth-enabled/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the previous post &lt;a href="https://zhaohuabing.com/post/2018-08-01-manage-onap-with-istio/">Manage ONAP Microservices with Istio Service Mesh&lt;/a>, we went through the steps of how to install Istio and integrate it with ONAP platform, it’s super simple and has nearly no impact to the existing projects. Now let’s enable Istio auth to secure the inter-service communication inside ONAP, it will need a little bit more efforts, but it’s worth with the benefits brought by it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manage ONAP Microservices with Istio Service Mesh</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2018-08-01-manage-onap-with-istio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2018-08-01-manage-onap-with-istio/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the previous post &lt;a href="https://zhaohuabing.com/post/2018-06-22-onap-with-service-mesh/">How service mesh can help during the ONAP Microservice journey&lt;/a>, we have discussed why the community wants ONAP to evolve towards Microservice architecture and how service mesh approach could help during the journey. Now it’s time to dip our toe in the water, let’s try out Istio with ONAP by following the below steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;h1 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>First, download installation scripts from ONAP Gerrit:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How service mesh can help during the ONAP Microservice journey</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2018-06-22-onap-with-service-mesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2018-06-22-onap-with-service-mesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.onap.org/announcement/2018/06/12/onap-announces-availability-of-beijing-release-enabling-a-deployment-ready-platform-for-network-automation-and-orchestration">ONAP Beijing is available now&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ONAP, as part of LF Networking, now accounts for more than 65% of global subscriber participation through carriers creating a harmonized, de-facto open source platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>While it&amp;rsquo;s so exciting to see that more operators are deploying ONAP in their commercial network, ONAP community realizes that there are still somewhere we can improve to smooth the deployment process. For example, instead of deploying ONAP as a whole, users may just want to pick some modules, integrate these modules with their existing system to get a customized ONAP solution. Actually, this is a very usual usage scenario in open source world. So it should be easy to tailor ONAP to suit the different scenarios and purposes for various users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LFN ONAP Beijing Release Developer Forum: MSB to Support Carrier Grade ONAP Microservice Architecture with Service Mesh</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2017-11-11-onap-msb-to-support-carrier-grade-onap-microservice-architecture-with-service-mesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2017-11-11-onap-msb-to-support-carrier-grade-onap-microservice-architecture-with-service-mesh/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this session, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the MSB Plan for R2 and Beyond. I&amp;rsquo;ll also discuss the OMSA(ONAP Microservice Architecture): the vision of ONAP Microservice Architecture to support Carrier-Grade requirements of ONAP Microservices, which includes Service Orchestration, Service Discovery, Inter-service Communication, Service Governance and Service Monitoring and External API Gateway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ONAP Architecture Principle: ONAP modules should be designed as microservices: service-based with clear, concise function addressed by each service with loose coupling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LFN ONAP Developer Event: Microservice Bus Tutorial</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2017-09-25-onap-microservice-bus-tutorial-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2017-09-25-onap-microservice-bus-tutorial-/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Microservices Bus(MSB) provide a reliable, resilient and scalable communication and governance infrastructure to support Microservice Architecture including including service registration/discovery, external API gateway, internal API gateway, client SDK. It&amp;rsquo;s a pluggable architecture so it can integrate with auth service provider to provide centralized Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization. MSB also provides a service portal to manage the REST APIs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MSB doesn’t depend on a specific environment. It can work in bare metal, virtual machine or containerized environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ONS ONAP Minisummit: Microservice Powered Orchestration Architecture</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2017-04-14-onap-microservice-powered-orchestration-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2017-04-14-onap-microservice-powered-orchestration-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this session, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the MSB(Microservice BUS) project we have been using in OPEN-O as the fabric for Microservice communications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I will start with why we choose Microservice Architecture in OPEN-O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I’d like to talk about the challenges we were facing when we turn to the microservice approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, How we address these challenges in OPEN-O with the help of Microservice BUS
And what’s the potential benefit MSB could bring to ONAP.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LFN ONAP Developer Event: MSB Technical Deep Dive and ONAP Use Cases</title><link>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2017-04-02-onap-msb-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lopins.github.io/hugo-template/post/2017-04-02-onap-msb-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this session, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the MSB(Microservice BUS) project we have been using in OPEN-O as the fabric for Microservice communications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I will start with why we choose Microservice Architecture in OPEN-O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, I’d like to talk about the challenges we were facing when we turn to the microservice approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, How we address these challenges in OPEN-O with the help of Microservice BUS
And what’s the potential benefit MSB could bring to ONAP.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>